An Annotated Calendar of the Letters of Charles Darwin in the Library of the American Philosophical Society 1799-1882 Mss.B.D25
American Philosophical Society
- Non-Carroll Darwin Materials
  - Letter to Professor Errera, 1893 October 29; Darwin, Francis, Sir, 1848-1925
    Francis apologizes to Professor Errera for having written and misspelled the Professor's name in pencil "that won't rub out" on the letters from his father (Charles Robert Darwin). He explains the necessity of adding the receipients' names to all the letters, since there were "hundreds addressed to 'Dear Sir'.
  - Letter to Mrs. [K.M.H.] Lyell, Jan. 22, 1896; 8x5-1/2; Brandis, Dietrich, Sir, 1824-1907
    Bonn, A.L.S. 4p. (see Lyell album,C Friendly letter. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Personal reminiscences of Charles Darwin and of the reception of the "Origin of species"., February 12, 1909; Bryce, James Bryce, Viscount, 1838-1922
    Commemoration of the centenary of Charles Darwin's birth and the fiftieth anniversary of the publication of the"Origin of species"(November 24, 1859). 21p. sq.Q. [1909]. Corrected manuscript. (Typewritten with manuscript corrections). Read before the American philosophical society, April 23, 1909. Printed in Proceedings, v.48,p.iii. Formerly B D25 b
  - Undated
  - Letter to Mrs. [K.M.H.] Lyell, Jan. 10, undated; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Brandis, Dietrich, Sir, 1824-1907
    Richmond, A.L.S. 4p. (see Lyell Album, C) Friendly letter. Botany. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to Bernard Studer, Jan. 20, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to [Thomas Henry] Huxley, 6 February, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882.
    Down, n.y. A.L.S. 1p. Agrees with Huxley's letter published in "The Week".
  - Letter to [Leonard] Horner, Feb. 14, undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Lyell album, C) Natural history. Mentions Agassiz. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to Sir Charles Lyell, March 20, undated; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Forbes, Edward, 1815-1854
  - Letter to Karl Vogt, April 12, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to [Mrs. Katherine M.H. Lyell], April 21, undated; 7x4-1/2; Brown, Robert, 1773-1858
    Monday, A.L. 2p. (see Lyell album,C) Friendly letter. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter J. de C. Sowerby, May 4, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Journal extracts, May 15-Dec. 4, undated; 13x8; Donnelly, Ignatius, 1831-1901
    Xerox of typed D. 2p. (see Darwin papers.) Refers to correspondence with Darwin. B D25.170
  - Letter to Bernard Studer, July 4, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to Sir Charles Lyell, [bart.], July[?], 25/26, undated; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    Berlin, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Seal. Concerning geology and volcanoes.
  - Letter to Karl Vogt, Aug. 7, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to ----, Sept. 24, undated; 7x4-1/2; Milne-Edwards, H. (Henri), 1800-1885
    Monday, A.L.S. 1p. (see Lyell Album, C.) Refuses invitation. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to [Forel], Sept. 28, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to [Charles Lyell], Oct. 17, undated; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Lyell album, C) Invitation to tea. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to [R. Irwin Lynch], Oct. 23, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to Lady [Mary Horner] Lyell, Dec. 6, undated; 7x4-1/2; Forbes, Edward, 1815-1854
    Kent, A.L.S. 2p. (see Lyell album, C) Friendly letter. Natural history. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Lloyd] Horner, Dec. 23, undated; 7x4-1/2; Brown, Robert, 1773-1858
    Saturday, A.L.S. 2p. (see Lyell album, C Friendly letter. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, Dec. 23, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to, Sunday, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to Sir Charles [Lyell], Sunday, undated; 7x4-1/2; Wallace, Alfred Russel, 1822-1913
    St. Mark's Crescent, Sunday. A.L.S. 2p. (see Lyell album, C) Concerning Huxley. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to Lady [Mary Horner] Lyell, Wednesday, undated; 7x4-1/2; Forbes, Edward, 1815-1854
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 2p. (see Lyell album, C) Friendly Letter. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ticknor, Friday, undated; 8x5; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Friday. A.L.S. 1p. (see Lyell album, C) News of Tilton. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to Sir Charles Lyell, Saturday morning, undated; 6x4; Haeckel, Ernst Heinrich Philipp August, 1834-1919
    Saturday morning. A.L.S. 1p. In German. (see Lyell album, C). Formerly B D25.L1.
  - C[harles]R[obert Darwin to, Saturday Evening, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Charles Darwin to, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to [Lady Marion Shaw Bell.], undated; 4-1/2x7; Bell, Charles, Sir, 1774-1842
    A.L. 2p. Fragment. (see Lyell album, C) Concerning Mr. and Mrs. Horner. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Report on wings sent by... of Sedalia, MO to the College of Surgeons for examination, undated; Blair, R.A.
  - Manuscript., undated; 9x7-1/2; Bell, Charles, Sir, 1774-1842
    A.D. 2p., end. (see Lyell album, C) Natural history. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - The Fertilization of Orchids, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to Mrs. [K.M.H.] Lyell., undated; 7x4-1/2; Edgeworth, Michael Pakenham, 1812-1881
  - Distribution of mollusca., undated; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Forbes, Edward, 1815-1854
    A.D. 3p. and end.
  - Letter to Sir Charles Lyell, undated; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
  - Letter to Sir Charles Lyell, undated; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
  - Charles [Robert] Darwin to, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
  - Letter to [Charles] Lyell., undated; 7x4-1/2; Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sir, 1817-1911
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Lyell album C) Concerning an earthquake. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to Sir Charles Lyell, undated; 6-1/2x5; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    [bart]. A.L. 1p.and add. In French. Fragment. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Dame Pertz., undated; 9x5-1/2; Humboldt, Alexander von, 1769-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. In German. (see Lyell album, C.) No translation made. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - List of seeds and plants, undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
    A list of seeds and plants in Darwin's hand whose purpose is undisclosed.
  - Letter to Charles Lyell, undated; 8x5; Lindley, John, 1799-1865
    Bloomsbury. A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. (see Lyell album, C) Botany. Formerly B D25.L1.
  - Letter to Sir Charles Lyell, [bart]., undated; 6-1/2x5; Lyell, Charles, Sir, 1797-1875
    A.L. 1p.and add. In French. Fragment. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Sir] C[harles] Lyell, [bart.], Bloomsbury, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Lyell, Charles, Sir, 1797-1875
    Friday. A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Sir Charles [Lyell, bart.]., undated; 7-1/4x4-1/4; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to "Dear Sir;", undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882.
    Down, Beckenham, Kent, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks, but thinks he should present work on physics to someone who would better appreciate it.
  - Letter to [Sir] C[harles] Lyell, [bart.], Bloomsbury, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Sedgwick, Adam, 1785-1873
  - Origin of Species, undated; 13x8-1/4; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
    [On the origin of species]. A.D. 5 leaves. B D25.57
  - Sketches of Charles Darwin, Mrs. Darwin, etc., undated; B D25.160; 10x14; Goodwin, Albert, 1845-1932
    D. 1p. OS.
  - Letter to [R. Irwin Lynch?], undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882.
    Down, Beckenham, Kent, A.L.S. 3p. Concerns phenomenon of sleep in plants. Asks if Lynch noticed if the plant Erythrina crista-galli sleeps.
  - Letter to "Dear Marshall;", undated; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882.
    Down, Beckenham, A.L.S. 3p. Asks if he knows how deep down earthworms make tubular burrows. Concerning earthworms.
  - Hugo de Vries and Charles Darwin., undated; 11x8-1/2; Van der Pas, Peter W
    D. 29p. (see Darwin papers.) Presented by the author; May 1, 1968. This may be used, but not quoted. B D25.163
  - Pass issued to Jas. Gough., undated; 4 1/2" x 2 3/4"; Zoological society of London
    Printed N. S: Charles Darwin 1p. B D25.111
  - Letter to [Frederick Wollaston Hutton], undated; 7x4-1/2; Hutton, Frederick Wollaston, 1836-1905
    Down, Bromley, Kent, Wednesday [1861-1862?]. A.L.S. 1p. (see Darwin papers.) Acknowledges issue of the journal of the Horticultural Society containing Dr. Herbert's paper. B D25.14
  - Letter to [Charles Fox], undated; 8x5; Fox, Sarah Hustler, 1800-1882
    Friday. A.L. 2p. Incomplete. (see Darwin papers.) Hopes he gets better. Some problems of natural history. On same sheet as Darwin to Fox; June 4. B D25.149
  - Letter to ----, undated; Darwin, Charles,1809-1882.
    Down, Beckenham, Kent, A.L.S. 2p. Asks if any sort of gelatin of animal matter is ever used in preparing belladonna or digitalis.
  - Letter to [R Irwin Lynch?], undated; Darwin, Charles,1809-1882.
    Down, Beckenham, Kent, A.L.S. 1p. Mr. Dyer suggested Darwin examine leaves of young plants. Asks for seeds from Lynch.